<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bollywood on 404EngineerNotFound</title><link>https://deepskandpal.github.io/tags/bollywood/</link><description>Recent content in Bollywood on 404EngineerNotFound</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 15:39:28 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://deepskandpal.github.io/tags/bollywood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bollywood needs a hard reset</title><link>https://deepskandpal.github.io/thoughts/bollywood/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jun 2025 15:39:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://deepskandpal.github.io/thoughts/bollywood/</guid><description>&lt;p>So I watched or rather tried to watch this weeks movie releases. I had 2 options one was House full 5 and the other was a few weeks old but new to OTT bhul chuk maaf. Now I personally never found any housefull movie funny not even the first one. Except that one dialogue by Ritesh Deshmukh regarding &amp;ldquo;Biwi&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Behen&amp;rdquo; in the first one I have mostly cringed. Pardon me if my sense of humour is not keeping up with the times but I grew up watching comedies of Priya Darshan and Akshay kumar. Raju hirani, and too some extent I find Rohit shetty older films also funny with Chennai Express being my favorite from his Filmography. So I would think of myself as someone who under stands what &amp;ldquo;Brain rot comedy&amp;rdquo; is in Hindi Cinema context. I don&amp;rsquo;t really understand why we have moved on to accept absolutely mediocre films with sub par production/acting/writing/production-design/music/dance in the name of &amp;ldquo;oH bUt iTs tImE pASS dON&amp;rsquo;t tHinK tOO mUch&amp;rdquo; . If i pay money for something I am liable for getting what is expected in return. Let me draw a parallel. If you go to a restaurant to have creamy shahi paneer and the waiter serves you the Now known to everyone &amp;ldquo;Analogue&amp;rdquo; Paneer. Which we all know is not real paneer and also bad for your health but it tastes almost like an original paneer. Would you accept my argument &amp;ldquo;But bro itne paise mai aisa hi paneer milega restaurant ko bhi toh paisa banane hai&amp;rdquo;. Won&amp;rsquo;t you feel cheated that in the name of paneer garbage was fed to you? ( a seemingly paneer looking garbage but still gargbage)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>