<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Designing Machine Learning Systems: An Iterative Process for Production-Ready Applications on 404EngineerNotFound</title><link>https://deepskandpal.github.io/bookshelf/design-ml-system/</link><description>Recent content in Designing Machine Learning Systems: An Iterative Process for Production-Ready Applications on 404EngineerNotFound</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://deepskandpal.github.io/bookshelf/design-ml-system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter 1: Overview of Machine Learning Systems</title><link>https://deepskandpal.github.io/bookshelf/design-ml-system/chapter-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://deepskandpal.github.io/bookshelf/design-ml-system/chapter-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://aistudio.google.com/prompts/19Kbu6lIbeuASE0ER7Hc3puDMRZYY6_Z4">Prompt&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The chapter opens with a great example: Google Translate&amp;rsquo;s multilingual neural machine translation system back in 2016. This was a landmark – deep learning making a massive, tangible impact at scale. It showed the world the power of modern ML.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since then, as the book says, ML has &amp;ldquo;found its way into almost every aspect of our lives.&amp;rdquo; This is true. At FAANG, we see this daily – from the recommendations you get, to how your photos are enhanced, to how we optimize our data centers.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chapter 2: Introduction to Machine Learning Systems Design</title><link>https://deepskandpal.github.io/bookshelf/design-ml-system/-chapter-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://deepskandpal.github.io/bookshelf/design-ml-system/-chapter-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>This chapter will guide us through:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Objectives&lt;/strong>: Why are we building this system in the first place?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Requirements&lt;/strong>: What qualities must our system possess? (Think reliability, scalability).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Iterative Process&lt;/strong>: Spoiler: building ML systems is rarely a straight line.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Problem Framing&lt;/strong>: How do we turn a vague business problem into a concrete ML task? This is crucial.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>And finally, a bit of a philosophical discussion: &lt;strong>Data vs. Algorithms&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ll see a recurring theme: &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Not so soon!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> Before you jump to coding a model, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of critical thinking and planning. This upfront work is what separates a successful, production-ready ML system from a science project. This chapter is packed with concepts that will come up in ML system design interviews.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>