<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - 404 engineer not found</title>
        <link>https://deepskandpal.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | 404 engineer not found</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 22:03:56 &#43;0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://deepskandpal.github.io/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Knowledge Mastrubation</title>
    <link>https://deepskandpal.github.io/posts/knowledge-mastrubation/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 22:03:56 &#43;0530</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://deepskandpal.github.io/posts/knowledge-mastrubation/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Disclaimer: If you don&rsquo;t read more than an insta post or a tweet or a restaurant menu. OR if the last &ldquo;book&rdquo; you owned was that notes on that one chapter you hated in college then this article IS NOT FOR YOU, GO PICK UP A FUCKING BOOK AND READ. THE END. FUCK OFF AND OPEN A BOOK ASSHOLE.</p>
<p>But if you have made it this far that means you read and you are dumb (I know surprising right how can you be well read and still be dumb). So come my child let me ruin your day.</p>
<p>Now before I ruin reading for you let me tell you my self defined, Ignorant and no peer reviewed credentials as an &ldquo;avid reader&rdquo;. Here it is.</p>
<p>Whatever number books you have ever read in your life I have read 10 books more than that (I am 69% sure) And I own a Gold plated 22 volumes world book encyclopedia set (all the way from A to Z take that Amazon 100K $ logo) since the time I could say the word BOOK and they were my only friends for a very long time.I have a maxed-out-on-space kindle, And a book cupboard containing All the hardcovers I have read and completed which is bigger than my current clothes cupboard.</p>
<p>So with this established.Lets just assume I know more about reading than you. You can disagree and I don&rsquo;t care. You are reading and I am writing so shut up and continue reading.</p>
<p>So why is reading bad for you. In one simple sentence. It gives a false sense of accomplishment. It does not apply when we read fiction (if you only read fiction something is wrong with you, I don&rsquo;t know what but you should get yourself checked). It is applicable when you read book for self-improvement of any kind (Again if you ONLY read self help something is wrong with you, I don&rsquo;t know what but you should get yourself checked). It is very safe to assume that something is wrong with me too. Based of what I have written and published till now and this article, If you think I need help or a hug, you are probably right. Only beautiful people who are celebrities are okay in this world. Only people who have families are normal. Those Insta models you jerk off too (yes both of you Guys and Gals) they are happy and normal. Living their life.</p>
<p>Haha if you believe the above line you are fooled my friend. As Will Mcavoy would say in Newsroom &ldquo;There are 2 kinds of people in this world. People who think they are normal. And People who know there is no such thing&rdquo;. We all are bonkers about something or someone. We just are very good at hiding it, from the world from ourselves. Let me repharase in a much simpler way YOU ARE CRAZY, YOU JUST DON&rsquo;T KNOW IT YET. Or maybe you do, in that case. Congratulation. You are one step closer to a happier life.</p>
<p>Haha fooled again. We will cover normal, abnormal later.</p>
<p>Coming to Reading. Again like I mentioned before. I am on a self discovery journey and this notepad you are seeing or reading contains all the garbage I think which I want to throw away. Why not do it privately? because I am not a pussy asshole. I don&rsquo;t mind sharing what I think about this world, with the world. Also If I cannot take criticism on the internet then I don&rsquo;t have balls to be a writer. So I think of it like a practice for the future When I do write on the internet for money. If you found this blog even after me not promoting it. Great you have lot of free time use it. If you want to disagree , Great I am in favour of pluralism. If you want to fight over my views, Great see you in a boxing ring. Also get a life.</p>
<p>The one thing I learned while Reading so much for so many years is. For me it was less about gaining any knowledge and more about escaping reality. Hate your situation. Pick up Harry Potter, you would love the world and will be lost in it. Want to feel like you are doing something about your life. Pick any book in one of those areas where you feel you are lacking:</p>
<ol>
<li>Weight loss: Don&rsquo;t lose your mind, Lose your weight</li>
<li>Money issues: Psychology of Money</li>
<li>Dating problems: Models, How to attract women through Honesty (If you are a gal reading this then you don&rsquo;t have dating problems, simply be feminine i.e &ldquo;traditonal beauty&rdquo; and submissive in front of the dude you want to fuck and he will leave US presidency for you. Ask Monica lewinsky)</li>
<li>Want to be an entreprenuer: Dream with your eyes open; Steve Jobs ; Shoe Dog</li>
<li>Want to learn new things the new way and stick with it till completion: Ultra-learning</li>
<li>Want to make new habits for a better life: Atomic Habits</li>
</ol>
<p>These are some of the categories I could think of anyone would be unhappy with in their life. And the books I have suggested are some of the best in the world for the same. So you are welcome.</p>
<p>Have you ever jerked off (yes both of you guy or gal) if you have then you know, How when you complete you are both satisfied and feel guilty. That&rsquo;s what happens when you read too much about a particular topic which you are trying to improve upon.</p>
<p>I call this Knowledge Mastrubation (I did not coin the term.I am borrowing it. I read it in one of the 2 &ldquo;dating playbooks&rdquo; I bought. If this blog goes viral I promise I will mention the creator&rsquo;s name and his gumroad link). Just like mastrubation is not linked with sex. Knowledge Mastrubation is not linked with actual accomplishment. It boils down to theory and practical in the end. This is it this is the point. When you read a book you need to ask yourself a very important question, Why am I reading this? If this question doesn&rsquo;t pop up when you pick up that stack of papers. You are doing a disservice to yourself and you are probably better of not reading that book at all. There are so many Books I started reading and never finished. So many that I got the gist and just stopped midway since I could sense I cannot derive much from it anymore so it doesn&rsquo;t make sense for me to continue.</p>
<p>After years of reading I realized it&rsquo;s better to stop reading if the book is not interesting than to read it till completion. It feels like excessive mastrubation. That OCD of reading the last page when you hate what you are reading will drive you crazy. Sleepless nights and headaches are confirmed. And if you are weak then you might also end up puking. Don&rsquo;t read if you hate it. So you read the kindle sample finished it bought the book on AMAZON and now it doesn&rsquo;t hold up the same attention like that sample did. Cool chuck it its not worth your time, Its okay you wasted your money on it. But if you have netflix and pay for it monthly you already are okay with wasting money. Those 6$ were still well spent on that book. You bought that hard cover after reading the first 2 pages of it from Crossword now the next chapter feels like someone is trying to sexually assault you. Don&rsquo;t worry, try to return the book, if not give it to the rag picker. Or keep it like a trophy to show off. Whatever you do just DON&rsquo;T READ that garbage. Don&rsquo;t put your mind through that torture. It is already tired with all that excessive jerking off. Let me let you in on a industry trade secret. Authors are told by publishers to have &ldquo;killer openings&rdquo; simply for this reason. So that after reading a few pages you buy the book. A book at the end of the day is just like another product. It needs to sell to make money. Next time you feel &ldquo;tricked&rdquo; into buying a book. It&rsquo;s okay you are dumb.It&rsquo;s okay to be dumb sometimes. The system works because of dumb people like you and me.</p>
<p>This is the attention economy now. Who gets the most eye balls makes the most money. The older times when a book was supposed to be the &ldquo;Knowledge of the world&rdquo; is gone. Now every book has to compete with an iPAD with PUBG installed in it. That book is no match to the social media app(whichever you prefer, insta, twitter, snapchat, YT) on your phone. Books don&rsquo;t add value to your life like they used to. Most of it recycled garbage. Unless you are an experienced reader it would be next to impossible for you to differentiate between a good book to a bad one. So stop holding them up on a pedestal. It was written by a human like you and me.</p>
<p>And if you think reading will solve your problems or that its enough. let me tell you nobody got laid by reading pick up lines. Its only when you get a few drinks on your face or being called a creep a few times that you figure out what works. Hence ACTION will aways triump reading. Another secret I would let you in. YOU CAN TAKE ACTION without ANY KNOWLEDGE about that thing you want to improve at all.</p>
<p>Take Action get the ball moving. Then Add reading as a way to accentuate your Actions. That is one of the ways I found some improvement in a few things I am struggling right now.</p>
<p>And not every book deserves your attention. Sometimes a book might look attractive from outside or for a few pages might appear smart and funny. But as you get to know it better you realise what load of crap it is. In that case its ALWAYS better throw it away from your life. Rather than letting it ruin your peace</p>
<p>Throw that book away.</p>
<p>(PS: if you understood the last para you are not dumb you are smart. For rest live in confusion you idiot)</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Controversial</title>
    <link>https://deepskandpal.github.io/posts/controversial/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 16:24:45 &#43;0530</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://deepskandpal.github.io/posts/controversial/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I have been what most people call &ldquo;nice guy&rdquo;. If you don&rsquo;t know what nice guy means, congratulations you are one . Before Feb 2022 I would avoid any and all kinds of conflict. A difficult conversation regarding something as simple as getting money back from a friend used to sound terrifying (so many times I have just reluctantly forgiven the debt). Talking to service staff for anything I need also felt like a task (excuse me waiter can i get my supposedly hot food reheated. No. cool thanks I&rsquo;ll just consume this partly cold dish which I am going to pay full prize for quielty) (Will this cab which is supposed to go to any place I want if I am paying full prize for the ride PLEASE take me. No. Cool I will just walk next 12 KM thanks), You get the idea. The truth is I hated that life and at the end of 2021 I decided I would change it. I didn&rsquo;t know what all problems I had back then so I did what I do the best when I am not sure of something.</p>
<p>Sleep</p>
<p>Instead of partying like there is no tomorrow (which, when I do it, sometimes have almost lead to there being literally no tomorrow for me i.e almost dead). When I woke up it was a new day in 2022. 2022 fuck where are those flying cars I was promised back when I was kid? No flying cars just me overweight, unhappy, frustrated. But since I had a great sleep I woke with an elegant never-thought-of simple solution.</p>
<p>New year resolutions (hahaha, lol)</p>
<p>There is nothing wrong with new year resolutions, its the stupid hype around them and the unnecessary criticism if one does not stick to them. If you read James clear&rsquo;s &ldquo;Atomic habits&rdquo; you would realise the importance of Habits. New year resolutions are the best way to make new habits. So like a dumb fucker I made a list of things I would fix this year</p>
<ol>
<li>Change city (since I was living with my parents, not very sad, just a little bit)</li>
<li>Change Job (I was making comfortable money, But I am an ambitious greedy fucker and I wanted to make butt load of money doing what I already love)</li>
<li>Lose weight (We will cover that a bit later)</li>
<li>Cook (looks quite small compared to the rest of list but it wasn&rsquo;t. Again more on it later)</li>
<li>DATE (I am hetrosexual male, Me want women. This one would be interesting I promise)</li>
</ol>
<p>My goal was I should have Done 1 2 and 3 by first half of 2022 (6 months) and I should have set processes for good habits (remember Clear from above) for 4 and 5 by the end of year.</p>
<p>I have accomplised 1 and 2. For 3 my goal was wrong. I found 4 to be super easy. It is the 5th which turned out to be the most interesting and probably more difficult than I anticpated. Not the way you think, No I am not some lonely nerd who cannot keep a 2 sentence conversation with a random women. I am just a overconfident, arrogant nerd who cannot keep a women around for more than few months.Women have pined for me in the past (self-brag) and I have thought I don&rsquo;t deserve them or the happiness that comes with a relationship. It was difficult because it looked like a surface level &ldquo;Game&rdquo; problem but it turned out to be a deeper psychological one. Again my goal with 5th was wrong</p>
<p>So what does it have to do with controversy? or rather being controversial?</p>
<p>One of the &ldquo;dating play book I read&rdquo; (yes I did buy a 30$ dating play book. Make it 2) talked about how women like &ldquo;controversial men&rdquo;. This was way back during the inital days of my self-discovery journey (I am on it for last 6 months and will probably be on it for the rest of my life). But like everything else in my life that has happened. I set out to find something but I ended up finding something else.</p>
<p>You see. What the &ldquo;author&rdquo; was trying to communicate when he gave that bullshit advice was women like men who have &ldquo;controversial opinion&rdquo; over men who don&rsquo;t have any &ldquo;controversial opinion&rdquo; (nice guy remember ? you are one of them). It makes you more &ldquo;attractive&rdquo;. HENCE YOU SHOULD BE CONTROVERSIAL WITH WOMEN.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s all bullshit. But it got me thinking and my weird brain started making connections everywhere with this &ldquo;controversial men are sexy&rdquo;. Why was he (Author)claiming this if it sound bullshit to me? (good thought exercise. Next time. When you hear a point from someone which you think sounds bullshit try to ask yourself.Why is this person making this bullshit point?).You see what he &ldquo;Really&rdquo; should have said was women like men who don&rsquo;t always AGREE with everything and have their mind of their own. If there is something they find unaccpetable the just say it no matter how &ldquo;Ignorant&rdquo; or &ldquo;Controversial&rdquo; it might be. It does not mean you should have an unpopular opnion just for the sake of it. THAT WAS WHAT THAT FUCKER WAS IMPLYING.FAKE YOUR UNPOPULAR OPINION TO GET LAID.</p>
<p>(Disclaimer: I will make a lot of points and opinions linked to this topic of women and dating, because currently this intrigues me, If you don&rsquo;t like it let me suggest something that will save both our time. STOP READING my blog)</p>
<p>So why does this all matter? What is the point? There is no point. Not everything has a summary or a moral. Somethings are just there. The truth is people don&rsquo;t become honest or express their honesty because they are afraid to be mistook or misinterpreted. The world does not reward for honesty it prefers or rewards lying. That is the whole basis of today&rsquo;s politics. The one who can lie convincingly. Sales also involves a good deal of lying. So why shouldn&rsquo;t you trying to fuck some chick be devoid of any truth?</p>
<p>This is basis of being a nice guy/conflict avoider/people pleaser (pick the term you are more comfortable with, they are all the fucking same). But what I am trying to say is the implication of you or anyone trying to hold back their true feelings or thoughts and not giving it voice goes beyond you screwing a chick. We do it even in places where there is no sexual expectation. We do it with friends, families, colleagues, bosses, online. We are scared of someone twisting our words and make us look like assholes. I was and to some extend still am a &ldquo;nice guy&rdquo;. Simply because I don&rsquo;t want unnecessary trouble. Which to some extend might look fine. But isn&rsquo;t that too much fuck to give about others opinion? Isn&rsquo;t the whole Mark Manson philosophy based on the idea of &ldquo;Not giving a fuck?&rdquo;</p>
<p>The rareity of an open minded unfiltered asshole man is such that when one does come across one, other men (&ldquo;unframed men&rdquo;) start throwing respect at him and women their underwear. What I have understood after some soul searching is, its next to impossible to not have a controversial opinion about anything. We are all human and we do disagree with something in the world, We all DO have a problem with something in our surrounding. We just hold back. You don&rsquo;t have to be controversial . YOU ALREADY ARE CONTROVERSIAL. You just keep lying to yourself like a little bitch that you are not.</p>
<p>So now the zillion dollar question What the hell is poltically correct?</p>
<p>Today the world wants you to lie. Lie about who you are, lie about what you think, lie about what you feel. They want you to confirm to society. Which you would have to at least till the point you escape it (By being rich, it&rsquo;s that simple). If you stand out or don&rsquo;t confirm to the politics of the surrounding (Right or Left) and if you are a nobody.You are fucked. This is when people become politically correct.</p>
<p>Should you become one? I don&rsquo;t know, I am not a self-help guru, twitter is filled with them. With a few days of research you can find really good ones. They will tell you whats right and wrong.</p>
<p>I will just say what I have done or understood.</p>
<p>My life became much more easier by balancing between lying and being honest.</p>
<p>(More on that later)</p>]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Brain Dump</title>
    <link>https://deepskandpal.github.io/posts/brain-dump/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 15:51:43 &#43;0530</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://deepskandpal.github.io/posts/brain-dump/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I am sorry if you landed here. It&rsquo;s not my fault though but still I will apologise. You are going to waste your time here. If you are smart you have already left but if you are dumb like me then let me Introduce you.. to the 4 weird russian texts just below the header (It came with the theme don&rsquo;t know how to fix it will probably in the future). If you made it this far then you are truly lonely but it also shows you have great patience for &ldquo;reader payoff&rdquo;. That being the case I would recommend reading lord of the rings It&rsquo;s insanely long but has a lot of readers payoff suprisingly at the exact moments where it starts to lose you (Tolkien is a genius). But if you are still reading (hats off). Let me tell you the purpose of this &ldquo;blog&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s nothing. It&rsquo;s just a journal for the mental thoughts I have every now and then. Why couldn&rsquo;t I get a notebook and &ldquo;jorunal&rdquo; like those Twitter self-help &ldquo;gurus&rdquo; because I believe in the idea of sharing thoughts. Quite normal right? No I don&rsquo;t mean polished final products like a fucking novel(yes baby swears will also be here). I meant unfiltered, unedited genuiune gut feelings with no polish what so ever combined with lets say some &ldquo;rational thinking&rdquo; and a few &ldquo;facts&rdquo;(hard to get any facts these days).
Everyone on the internet pretends to be &ldquo;cool&rdquo; some pretend to be &ldquo;cool&rdquo; but come of as dumb. I am trying out something different genuine (I would hardly consider this different considering zukerberg did the exact same thing when he wrote a blog and now he is a billionaire sociopath who controls have the world&rsquo;s arse). Blogs have been their till ages and people have been sharing their unfiltered thoughts also since ages. I am just trying to do the same. I am not trying to stand out or create the next viral thread like &ldquo;how to get rich without getting lucky&rdquo;. I am trying to be in those few people who still use the internet to share what they feel and what they think without any expectations.
So if you have reached this point and are disappointed because there was no readers payoff you were expecting, Haha jokes on you fucker.</p>]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
