<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - 404 engineer not found</title>
        <link>https://deepskandpal.github.io/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | 404 engineer not found</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 15:51:43 &#43;0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://deepskandpal.github.io/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Brain Dump</title>
    <link>https://deepskandpal.github.io/posts/brain-dump/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 15:51:43 &#43;0530</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://deepskandpal.github.io/posts/brain-dump/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I am sorry if you landed here. It&rsquo;s not my fault though but still I will apologise. You are going to waste your time here. If you are smart you have already left but if you are dumb like me then let me Introduce you.. to the 4 weird russian texts just below the header (It came with the theme don&rsquo;t know how to fix it will probably in the future). If you made it this far then you are truly lonely but it also shows you have great patience for &ldquo;reader payoff&rdquo;. That being the case I would recommend reading lord of the rings It&rsquo;s insanely long but has a lot of readers payoff suprisingly at the exact moments where it starts to lose you (Tolkien is a genius). But if you are still reading (hats off). Let me tell you the purpose of this &ldquo;blog&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s nothing. It&rsquo;s just a journal for the mental thoughts I have every now and then. Why couldn&rsquo;t I get a notebook and &ldquo;jorunal&rdquo; like those Twitter self-help &ldquo;gurus&rdquo; because I believe in the idea of sharing thoughts. Quite normal right? No I don&rsquo;t mean polished final products like a fucking novel(yes baby swears will also be here). I meant unfiltered, unedited genuiune gut feelings with no polish what so ever combined with lets say some &ldquo;rational thinking&rdquo; and a few &ldquo;facts&rdquo;(hard to get any facts these days).
Everyone on the internet pretends to be &ldquo;cool&rdquo; some pretend to be &ldquo;cool&rdquo; but come of as dumb. I am trying out something different genuine (I would hardly consider this different considering zukerberg did the exact same thing when he wrote a blog and now he is a billionaire sociopath who controls have the world&rsquo;s arse). Blogs have been their till ages and people have been sharing their unfiltered thoughts also since ages. I am just trying to do the same. I am not trying to stand out or create the next viral thread like &ldquo;how to get rich without getting lucky&rdquo;. I am trying to be in those few people who still use the internet to share what they feel and what they think without any expectations.
So if you have reached this point and are disappointed because there was no readers payoff you were expecting, Haha jokes on you fucker.</p>]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
